Ready, set, go, we step over the goal line
isse nou se de fumikomu gourain
Still, we don't know anything at all
bokura wa nanimo nanimo mada shiranu
We look back as we pass the line, and it's already gone
issen koete furikaeruto mou nai
Still, we don't know anything at all
bokura wa nanimo nanimo mada shiranu
Fiercely, fiercely we move on
udatte udatte udatteku
Drenched in glistening sweat
kirameku ase ga koboreru no sa
There probably were a lot of things we didn't remember
oboetenai koto mo takusan atta darou
Everyone was just a silhouette
daremo kare mo shiruetto
Let's become adults,
daiji ni shitai mono motte otona ni naru nda
holding on to things we want to cherish
And let's keep on protecting them at all times
donna toki mo hanasazu ni mamori tsudzukeyou
Then someday...
soshitara itsu no hi ni ka
We'll be able to laugh at it all
nanimo kamo o waraerusa
Like the light and nimble dancing
hirari to hirari to matteru
Of leaves taking flight
konoha ga tonde yuku
Escape vs. Pursuit
(キバ)なっ いい手だろ？
It's a good trick, eh?
この二次試験は こんな感じで
クールに決めようと思ってよ。
I want to wrap things up
in a cool way for the Second Exam.
(赤丸)ワンワン！
赤丸も肉球で
太鼓判押してくれたぜ。
Akamaru gave it his seal
of approval with his paws.
(シノ)悪くはないが
果たして それはクールなのか？
It's not bad, but...
I don't see what's so cool
about it.
(ヒナタ)私はいいと思う。
I think it's good!
なんか 泥臭くて
それでも頑張って➡
It's a little slow,
but it's trying hard to advance...
前に進もうとするところが
ナルト君ぽいっていうか。
It's kind of like something
Naruto would do... or...
ナルト関係ねえだろ！
This has nothing to do
with Naruto!
俺が考えたんだから。
あっ そうだね。
It's my idea, after all...
You're right...
今ごろナルト君 自来也様と
どこで修業してるのかな。
But I wonder where
Naruto is training
with Jiraiya Sensei around now?
知るかよ。 あっ。
Who knows!
《キバ : 何だ？ 今の》
キバ君？
What was that just now?
Kiba?
まあ やつが
どんな修業してようが➡
Anyway, who cares how he's training?
俺たちも この試験で
中忍になってよ➡
Let's pass these Chunin Exams
and get a leg up on him!
やつに差つけてやろうじゃねえか
いくぜ 紅第八班！
Let's go, Kurenai's Team 8!
(赤丸)ワンワン！
(ムヤミ)こんなもの こんなもの
こんなもの！
Damn scroll, damn scroll,
damn scroll...
(カザミ)
こうも運に見放されるとはな。
How can we be so unlucky?
(ブラミ)でも いいじゃない
カザミちゃん。
So what, Kazami?
(ブラミ)何回も狩りができて。
おいら楽しいよ。
We get to hunt...
and I'm enjoying this.
(ムヤミ)楽しくない 楽しくない
楽しくない。
It's no fun, it's no fun, it's no fun!
だが 予感がする。 次こそは
運が俺たちに味方すると！
But I have a feeling...
that Lady Luck will be on
our side next time!
ブラミ！ ムヤミ！ 俺たちはやれる。
Burami, Muyami! We can do it!
俺たちはできる！
俺たちは持っている！
I know we can!
We've got it!
フレー！ フレー！ 俺たち！
Three cheers for us!
Hip, hip, hooray!
(シノ)クールに決めるんじゃ
なかったのか？
Weren't you going
for a cool finish?
(キバ)上手くいかなかったんだから
しようがねえだろ。
I couldn't help it.
It didn't go right.
(キバ)だいたい 巻物の種類も
わかんねえのに➡
We don't even know what kind
of scroll we're fighting for,
戦おうってのがクールじゃねえよ。
and that's not cool.
(シノ)だったら どうすればいい？
So what do you suggest?
(キバ)ヒナタ お前 何かねえのか？
Hinata, can't you do something?
あるだろ 白眼で天の巻物
サーチするとかよ。
You can, right?
Like using your Byakugan
to search for Heaven scrolls.
巻物の種類までは…
キバ君 ダメ！
I can't go so far as seeing
what kind of scroll it is.
Kiba! Hush!
あん？ 今の聞かれたかな？
Do you think someone heard us?
うん 大丈夫だ。
It's all right!
(ブラミ)んなわけないじゃん！
You sure about that?
俺たちの予感は的中した
最高の運が転がり込んできたぞ。
Our hunch was right on target.
Luck has smiled upon us!
バカだ あいつらバカだ バカバカ！
Fools! Those guys are
fools, fools, fools!
木ノ葉の諸君
話は聞かせてもらった！
Hidden Leaf rivals!
We heard you loud and clear!
そうこなくっちゃな！
でないと困るんだよ！
Now that's good to know.
Otherwise, our little charade
would've been wasted...
俺たちも わざと聞かせるために
こんな三文芝居うったんだからな。
since we did it
just so you'd hear us.
エサにつられて
出てきたということは➡
Since you fell for the bait
and showed up, your scroll must be...
お前たちの巻物は…。
(ヒナタ)天！
Heaven!
なに？
(キバ)互いに欲しいものは
目の前にある。
What...?
We both have
what the other wants.
(キバ)あとは さっさと戦って
ぶんどるだけよ！
So let's get down to business...
and try to get it!
(カザミ)いいだろう！ 受けて立つ！
とう！
Fine! We accept your challenge!
ブハ～！
うぉ～！
う～っ！
フンッ！
におうな… てめえ。
ワンワン！
You smell, don't you?
赤丸 お前もそう思うか？
You're thinking
the same thing too, right, Akamaru?
こいつ 強えぞ。
This guy is strong.
う～っ！ ハッ。
フンッ！
(赤丸)ワンワン！
(キバ)擬獣忍法…。
Ninja Art! Beast Mimicry.
獣人分身！
Man Beast Clone!
へへっ！
クソッ だったら！
Damn it! Well then...
(キバ)牙通牙！
Fang Over Fang!
フゥ～。
《こいつの腹 攻撃を吸収して
弾き返しやがる》
This guy's belly... absorbs my attack
and fires it back!
《白眼！
Byakugan!
見える 361個のチャクラ穴。
I see them...
361 chakra points...
先手を取る》
I'll make the first move!
《これが噂に聞く 日向流柔拳。
So this is the Hyuga's famed
Gentle Fist...
点穴を突くことで 俺のチャクラを
掌中のものとする狙いか。
Her goal is to pierce my pressure points
to manipulate my chakra...
ならばこちらは
空気を利するとしようか！》
Well then, I'll just take
advantage of the air!
ハッ！
《ヒナタ : あの旗で
空気の流れや形を➡
He uses that flag to change the flow
and shape of the air currents...
新たに作り出している》
斬り裂くか。
Will you cut through it?
圧し潰す！
I'll crush you!
守護八卦六十四掌！
Protective 8 Trigrams 64 Palms!
(シノ)沈黙に気まずい思いを
することはない。 なぜなら➡
Don't let this awkward silence
bother you.
The reason is because,
初対面で
聞きたいことがないからだ。
it's our first meeting and
there's nothing I want to ask you.
僕は人見知りだから
やっぱり失礼するよ。
I'm shy...
so I'm going to excuse myself.
よっしゃ 来い。
All right! Come at me!
赤丸！ ぶち当たるんじゃないぞ。
Akamaru!
かぶりつけ！
(赤丸)ワン！
Don't slam into him!
Just bite him!
フン フン フン… フフフフフ～ン。
いった～！ クッ。
Ouch!
ク～ッ！
血が出た～！
痛い 痛い… 痛～い！
I'm bleeding!
Ouch! Ouch! Ouch!
よっしゃあ！ もう一度。
(赤丸)ワン！
All right! One more time!
なっ!?
(３人)あっ！
引っかかった 引っかかった！
We got you! We got you!
巻物は俺たちがいただいた！
Thanks for the scroll!
ワンワン！
クッソ…。
Damn it!
クソッ どうして？
Damn it! How the hell...?!
それぞれの戦いで 俺たちはまず➡
First thing we did was to
watch you all battle
誰が巻物を
持っているかを見定めた。
and figure out who had
what scroll.
すぐわかったもん。
It was easy...
お前 脇に変な力が入ってたぞ。
You put an unusual amount
of strength on your side.
((エヘッ。
(う～い！))
巻物の主がわかった時点で➡
Once we knew who had
the scroll, we all attacked.
全員で攻撃をかける。
１杯くわされたというわけか。
そんな…。
They pulled a fast one on us.
No way!
おいらのおかげだい。
It's all thanks to me.
I'm the one who saw the scroll!
巻物見つけたの おいらだもん。
俺たちのコンビネーションが
よかったからだ。
It's because we had
a good combo!
僕がやった 僕がやったんだ。
I did it! I did it!
ざけんなっ
その巻物は俺たちのもんだ！
Shut up!
That scroll belongs to us!
忍法…。
Ninja Art...
Smell Sphere!
スメル玉。
(キバ)ぐわ～！
(赤丸)キュゥ…。
体がしびれて。
My body... is getting numb...
動けない。
I can't move...
何なんだ この脳天を貫く衝撃は。
This shockwave feels like
it's piercing straight through my head.
クゥ～ン…。
俺と赤丸には わかる。
Akamaru and I can identify it.
こいつはニオイだ。
It's a scent...!
今まで嗅いだこともねえ➡
It's something we've never
smelled before...
とてつもねえニオイが 破裂したんだ。
It's an unbelievable scent explosion!
うぅ…。
あ～ うん。
おいらの体内で
熟成させた特製スメル。
It's a special scent that
I ferment inside my body.
ええニオイは いらんかね？
Want some more?
エヘヘヘヘヘ。
Why you—!
ふざけんな あぁ…。
キバ君たちの嗅覚で➡
Kiba, you two...
With your keen sense of smell...
このニオイを嗅いだら…。
this must be overpowering.
大丈夫？ キバ君。
Are you okay, Kiba?!
クッソ 大丈夫じゃねえよ。
Damn it... I'm not okay!
鼻が焼けそうにいってえ。
My nose feels like
it's on fire... Oww!
クウン クウン…。
あぁ…。
これは おいらのおかげだよ。
It's all thanks to me.
おいらの手柄だよね！
I did this, right?
ブラミ 何度言ったらわかる!?
Burami, get this through
your thick skull!
これはチーム力のなせる技だ。
むぅ。
It's because of our teamwork!
(キバ)クッソ～。
Damn it!
赤丸！
Akamaru!
あっ キバ君！
Kiba!
ぬぅ…。
ありゃ？ 立てるはずないのに。
What? You're not supposed
to be standing...
歩けるわけないのに
なんでなんで!?
You're not supposed
to be walking...
So how? How?
そう簡単には諦めてはくれねえか。
So they're not about
to give up yet, eh?
これがやつらのチーム力。
That's their teamwork...
ぬぅ えい！
くっ。
(キバ)ぜってえ取り返す。
I swear I'll get it back!
俺たちの巻物だ！
That's our scroll!
ええ 取り戻すまで諦めない。
Right! We're not giving up
until we get it back!
なぜなら中忍を
諦めるわけにはいかないからだ。
That's because we can't give up
on becoming chunin!
うざい。
So annoying.
口寄せの術。
Summoning Jutsu!
モグラン丸！
(モグラン丸)ブモ～。
Moguranmaru!
(ムヤミ)もうこいつらに用はない。
We're done with these guys!
とっとと帰る。
Let's get going.
おいらも乗ってく～。
I want a ride too!
土禁だからね。
Don't track any mud in here.
もう きついし 臭いし。
It's so crowded... and it stinks!
これがチーム力だ。
This is teamwork!
(キバ)この野郎 逃げようってのか。
Why you—!
Trying to run away?!
そうはさせねえ。
I won't let you!
俺たちは 敵地において
目的物を奪い➡
Our team specializes in snatching
our target item in enemy territory
これを必ず持ち帰ることに
特化したチームだ。
and taking it home without fail.
いただくものは いただいた。
We got what we came for.
This battle is over.
この時点で勝負はついた。
お前たちはもう
俺たちに触れることすらできねえ。
You guys can't touch us now.
(ブラミ)バッハハ～イ。
Bye!
て てめえら 待て おい。
You guys! Stop! Hey!
上等じゃねえかよ。
Well, that's fine with us.
てめえらが逃げ足を
自慢しようってんなら➡
Brag all you want about
your ability to get away.
俺ら紅班はな
感知能力に長けた追跡のプロだ。
Team Kurenai has the power
of sensory perception.
We're pros at tracking!
あらゆる状況に対処できるよう
クールに先手を打ってやる。
And we've got a cool guy
who assesses every situation calmly
and initializes action!
シノ！
Shino!
(シノ)俺たちは すでに
やつらに触れている。
We're already in contact.
なぜなら 俺の蟲が
あのモグラに付着しているからだ。
That's because my insects
are attached to that mole.
付着した蟲は雌。
I attached female insects...
そして 同種の雄は➡
and nothing will stop
the males of that species
その微かなニオイをも逃さない。
from chasing their delicate scent.
(キバ)俺も赤丸も
今は鼻が使いもんにならねえ。
My nose is still useless.
So is Akamaru's.
(キバ)お前の蟲が頼りだぜ。
We're counting on your insects!
任せろ 何も問題ない。
Don't worry.
I've got this covered.
近いぞ モグラは あの下辺りだ。
They're close!
The mole is under there somewhere!
よっしゃ！
All right!
ブモ～。
どうした ラン丸。
What is it, Ranmaru?
しまった 蟲に気づかれたか。
Damn it!
It sensed the insects!
だから 土禁って言ったろ。
This is why I said not
to track in any mud!
ラン丸は
きれい好きの敏感肌なんだよ。
Ranmaru has really sensitive skin
and is a clean freak!
(キバ)また地中に逃げるぞ。
They're escaping underground again!
クッソ。
大丈夫！
Damn!
It's all right. We're close enough
that I can see them!
ここまで接近すれば見える。
砂の中だろうと逃がさない。
They may be in the sand,
but I won't lose them!
ヒナタ。
Hinata!
白眼！
Byakugan!
見えた 10時の方角。
I see them! Over at 10 o'clock!
よっしゃ ぜってえ逃がさねえ。
Got it! They're not getting away!
１時の方角に転進。
They're turning towards 1 o'clock!
ヒナタ モグラ野郎との距離は？
Hinata! How close am I
to that mole?!
６メートル。
Six meters!
(キバ)赤丸 獣人分身 牙通牙。
Akamaru! Man Beast Clone!
Fang Over Fang!
目標 方向転換
10時の方角 ７メートル。
Target's changing directions!
10 o'clock, seven meters!
逃がさねえ！
I won't let ‘em get away!
今度は必ず… ぶち当てる。
This time...
I won't miss!
そのまま まっすぐ。
Go straight on ahead!
５メートル ４メートル。
Five meters! Four meters!
もうちょい引っ張るぜ。
I'm gonna close in
just a bit more...
３メートル。
Three meters!
な 何だ!?
W-What...?!
何だ？ これは…。
What is this?
砂が どんどん
やわらかくなって…。
The sand is getting
softer and softer...
あっ…。
(ブラミ)あれれ～？ もう
追いかけっこは終わりなの？
What?
Is this game of tag over already?
やべえぞ この砂… まるで…。
This isn't good.
The sand is like...
あぁ まるで 底なし沼だ。
Yes, it's like a bottomless swamp...
どんどん 沈んでいく。
I'm sinking quickly...
(シノ)やつらは これを狙っていた。
This is what they were after.
俺たちは やつらの作戦に➡
And we fell for it...
hook, line and sinker.
まんまと
かかってしまったようだ。
ク～ン ク～ン ク～ン…。
赤丸！
Akamaru!
沈め！ 沈め！ 沈め～！
Sink! Sink! Sink!
うっ… あわわわ！
ああ～！
ヒナタ！
Hinata!
これまでか。
So this is... it...
シノ～!!
Shino!
これで俺たちを
追うものは消えた。
No one will come after us now.
チームの勝利だ。
チームというより➡
Our team wins.
Actually, I outshined the rest
of the team.
おいらの プレーが
光ってたんじゃない？
僕の モグラン丸が頑張ったからだ。
It was all because my Moguranmaru
came through for us.
わかってない。
You guys don't get it.
(カザミ)まぁ あとは
速やかに ゴールするまでだ。
In any case, it will be smooth ride
to the finish line.
(ムヤミ)これで 僕たち
二次試験 突破だ。
We just aced the Second Exam.
赤丸！
Akamaru!
赤丸 しっかりしろ！
Akamaru! Get a hold of yourself!
こらぁ！
Hey!
赤丸…。
ワン ワン！
Akamaru!
よくやった 赤丸！
Good boy, Akamaru!
(キバ)お前の マーキングのおかげだぜ！
It was all thanks
to your Marking!
まったく よく思いついたぜ。
ワンワン！
That was really quick thinking!
これで 小便臭くなければ
パーフェクトだったのだが。
If we didn't smell like urine,
it would've been perfect...
大丈夫だよ 赤丸。
Don't worry, Akamaru.
そんなに臭くないから
気にならないよ。
It's not too smelly.
I'm fine with it.
いや におうな。
キバ君！
No... It stinks.
鼻が戻ってきたぜ。
え？
Kiba!
My nose is working again.
ヒナタ 白眼でやつらの姿 追えるか？
Hinata, can you pursue those guys
with your Byakugan?
もう 白眼の圏外に…。
They're out of range
for my Byakugan...
だったら 俺の出番だぜ！
Well then... It's my turn!
におうぜ。 こいつは
あのデブ野郎の強烈な肉臭だ！
I smell them.
It's the big guy's intense
body odor!
俺たちは 諦めねえ！
We're not giving up!
地獄の底まで追いかけて➡
We'll chase them to the depths of hell
and definitely get the scroll back!
必ず 巻物を奪い返すぞ！
うん！
おお！
– Right!
nando tatakitsukerarete mo
No matter how many times I get beat down
akiramerareru wake nado wanaku genten kaiki
I can't give up, so I go back to my basics
genjitsu to wa baibai shite
I wish we could say bye-bye to this reality
mukashi mitai ni waiwai shitai keredo
And have fun like we used to
sou mo ikanai nara kirihiraite mirya ii
But it doesn't work that way,
so let's carve out our own paths
nokori wazuka no shouki torimodoshite
I'll make you get back the little sanity you have left
me no mae no tobira kojiakete miseru
And then tear down the door in front of you
itsudemo sou nanda
That's the way it is
wasuregachina koto ga
The things you tend to forget
nani yori mo taisetsuna koto datte
Are the things that are the most important
nani ga machiukete iyou to kamawanai
I don't care what lies ahead
ame nimo makezu yami o terasu
The rain won't stop me from lighting up the darkness
kono kyoujin na kokoro ga areba
As long as I have this strong spirit
kono toki kono basho ni tsudoishi nakamatachi
Friends who gather at this time, at this place
mawari tsudzukeru sekai nanbitotari
The world keeps spinning, No one can stop it
tomo tomeru koto wa dekinai yo
The scent's gone!
Damn it!
What do we do?
There's no reason to despair.
That's because if we lose
our sense of smell,
＜今回の 「モクハチ」はリクエストスペシャル。
we still have the sense of sight.
これまで放送した曲のなかから➡
But they're outside
the range of the Byakugan...
皆さんのリクエストに
お応えいたします。
Then we'll go to
the outermost range!
更に 私 宮本隆治と…。
Bugs... We're depending on you!
松丸友紀が会場を飛び出し➡
東京・上野のアメヤ横丁で
リクエストをちょうだいいたします。
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"Unwavering Gutsiness"
We'll get back both
the Heaven and Earth scrolls!
皆さんのリクエスト曲は
入っていますでしょうか。
まずは この曲からです＞